thank you [Music]
in this video you will learn the fundamentals of the Godot gaming engine
we will start with the program setup and its key Concepts from there we will
cover a broad range of topics like Tire Maps animation players lights particle
effects shaders and user interfaces we will also cover more advanced topics
like skeleton animations and pathfinding if none of these words mean anything to
you don't worry I'm going to explain everything from scratch either way by
the end of the video you should have a strong understanding of how to create
basically any 2D game in Godot and you will also have a really good foundation
to start with 3D games before we begin a huge shout out to the sponsor of this
video not pass business when making a game you will end up with a lot of data
and backing all of that up is a nightmare you want to access your data
from anywhere from any operating system it should be convenient and it should be
secure both from hackers and from your house burning down
especially security is a major concern having my accounts hacked would be a
disaster for me and if it can happen to a large organization like city project
red or Linus Tech tips it could happen to me it could happen to you or it could
happen to your company not past business is an excellent
solution for all of that it safely stores your passport in one accessible
location and even enters your login credentials for you this makes it super
easy to save your game projects both on GitHub and Google Drive and have access
to them everywhere in the world it even lets you identify weak passwords and it
checks if any of your existing passwords has been leaked online on top of that
you can also set up biometric identification and use multi-factor
authentification notepass business also works with
unlimited passports including Wi-Fi credentials and credit cards so even for
things Beyond work it can be incredibly useful
if you want to sleep peacefully at night and not worry about your passwords check
out notepass business in the description and the link comment
if you go to notepass.com clearcode you will get a free month of trial for an
amazing password manager and also help me make more videos so definitely check
it out all right let's get started first of all
what is Kudo and how does it help you make a game
Fido is a game engine which means it is an app that lets you display images play
sounds capture user input and stuff like that the dough can do even more advanced
things like physics calculations pathfinding skeleton animations and
networking for multiplayer games all you have to do is to combine the various
Concepts and then create your game this could either be a 2d or a 3D game
Godot supports both other game engines you may have heard of are unity and
unreal there are hundreds of engines But ultimately they all do basically the
same thing one major advantage of Godot is that it
is entirely free and Community developed you never have to pay for anything you
don't have to sign away your soul in some legal text you don't even have to
create an account all you have to do is go to godotengine.com and click on
download latest then you can select a version that fits your operating system
although Godot will likely detect the right version for you on the website so
just click on Godot engine and you should be good with that you are
downloading a zip file and if you extract that you get two files one is
Godot itself the other would open a console
you can use the latter one for debugging but I would just ignore it so I'll just